Seattle, WA

(425) 635 - 8182

rameensahoo@gmail.com

rameensahoo.me

linkedin.com/in/rameensahoo

github.com/ramsahoo



Rameen Sahoo

SUMMARY

I am a Full-Stack Web and Mobile Developer and UI/UX Designer that primarily uses HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript with their relevant frameworks and databases. I have significant experience with user research and collaborating with developers to create web applications from the ground up. I maintain a detail-oriented mindset from 2+ years of experience in the tech industry.

EDUCATION

August 2021 - February 2022

Full-Stack Web and Mobile Development Certificate

Nucamp Coding Bootcamp

August 2014 - December 2018

B.A. in Sociology

University of Nebraska - Lincoln

SKILLS

- Angular
- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript/TypeScript
- Bootstrap
- React/Redux
- React Native
- Git
- Express
- MongoDB
- NoSQL
- SQL
- jQuery
- JSON
- Responsive Design
- Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present

Full-Stack Web and Mobile Developer and UI/UX

Designer (freelance)

I started learning web development through Nucamp Coding bootcamp, and I've been developing different projects for the past year. I've created a personal portfolio with a combination of HTML/CSS/JavaScript frameworks (primarily being jQuery), a counting app that's based on React, and a mock project about travelling to Africa, which primarily has bootstrap principles. I'm also in the process of creating a React Native mobile application and back-end project based on Express and Node.js. All projects can be found on my GitHub. The URL to my personal website is also listed above.

2019 - Present

Clinical Research Data Coordinator (Seattle, WA)

I'm working with a team of clinical researchers in the Genitourinary Urology Medical Oncology Department at the University of Washington. We coordinate clinical trials that lead to the FDA approval of cancer treatments. I am specifically coordinating databases and ensuring to send information and query responses by appropriate deadlines.

2014 - 2015

Architecture, Construction and Engineering Intern at ACE Mentor Program of Washington (Kirkland, WA)

I was mentored by working professionals in careers centered around design, engineering, and construction to create a mock sustainable project with a group of ~30 students.